Guide to the Student Newspapers Collection Student newspaper publications of the Danbury Normal School, Danbury Teachers College, Danbury State Teachers College, Western Connecticut State College and Western Connecticut State University RG 5.15.1
Western Connecticut State University Archives and Special Collections
- Inventory, 42054
  - The Inkling, March 1944 through June 1947, 1944-1947; 56489 (Box 2, Folder 7A - 14)
    January 1945, Volume II, No. 3 Music Center Presents Martha Graham; Dr. Jenkins aaddresses college; Cast photograph of "Comedy of Errors;" Editorial on "Evening Library Hours;" What's New on the Shelves [Library]' 1946 yearbook staff; Poetry by Lieut. Arthur Coladarci (Somewhere in the Pacific); Inkling joins Columbia Scholastic Press Association;" College Activity Fund Established.
    February 1945, Volume II, No. 4 Dr. Finch presents one aspect of world peace; War Time Measure--Eastern StatesCancelled; Review of the constitution of the Cooperative Goernment Association; Dr. K.Augusta Sutton lectures on Russia; Letter from Lt. Robert Thompson, Class '43; Inter-mural basketball tournament.
    March 1945, Volume II, No. 1 Cheney State Teachers College choir presents concert; Forum presents Dr. Phillips Bradley, Professor of Political Science at Queen college, Flushing, NY; Assembly speaker, Mrs. Charles House of the American Farm School in Salonica, Greece, addressed faculty, students, and guests at a special assembly; Clubs and Committee News; Assembly Cut Committee news; DTC forms a college choir.
    April 1945, Volume II, No. 2 Roosevelt's Death; students travel to New York City to see "The Tempest"; Assembly Bulletin; Science department to be expanded; DTC opens national clothing drive in town; Dr. Yu Gwan Chen lectures on China.
    May 1945, Volume II, No. 3 CGA elect Claire Kelley, Floriene Judell, and Marie Golder; Editorial "Thoughts on V-E Day;" CGA suggested constitutional revisions; Dates and Events column; Assembly Bulletin.
    June 1945, Volume II, No. 4 Students to graduate in December; Senior Memorial Day outing at Squantz Pond; Seniors given banquet; Entire school attends Danbury High School band concert; The Seniors Speak column; Danbury Players close season with plays, music and vocal selections; Class Day Exercises; Women's Athletic Association selects leaders for 1945-46; Kappa Delta Pi Initiates; Sport Finale; State grants fifty additional student scholarships; War Loan dance; Calendar for 1945-46; Outdoor fireplace is gift from senior class.
    October 1945, Volume II, No. 5 Reception for new members of the faculty and new students; Inkling apprentices chosen; new faculty member Miss Mary Swokla; Miss Alice S. Tucker, Fairfield Hall dietitian; Archery Tournament at the University of Connecticutto "Meet Our Executives" (list of students to head student government and clubs).
    November 1945, Volume II, No. 6 Dr. Finis E. Engleman to speaks during Assembly for National Education Week; Faculty considers plan for curriculum improvement; Musical Commentary; Assembly News; Dr. Grant E. Finch shows two-reel movie of a trip he took to South America; Junior Play "Harriet."
    December 1945, Volume II, No. 7 Senior-Faculty Dinner Final Social Event; Christmas Graduation, Class of '46; "Inkspots" column; The War is Over article; Campus Casuals column.
    January 1946, Volume II, No. 8 "New Era Stimulates Far-Reaching Plans" on education; "Welcome" editorial directed to men and women from the armed forces; The Dramtic Club petitioned Council for a charter; "We Asked The Questions" article; DTC basketball season begins.
    April 1946, Volume III, No. 2 Mr. Burton Cooks joins faculty; "Yesterday and Today" fashion show; "How to meet men" article; Inkspots colume; Cooperative Government Elections Second Week in May;" "The Power and the Glory," excerpts from Freshman and Sophomore term papers on What Makes America Great; Gertrude Braun will teach as a memberof the History Department.
    May 1946, Volume III, No. 3 The Conference of Elementary School Principals in Western Connecticut held at DTC; CGA Elections; DTC's Annual Spring Drama Festival; "We Were Listening" column; new World Student Service Club; DTC to have blazers made up in school colors.
    June 1946, Vol. III, No. 4 Dr. Mary Langmuir discusses marriage at Assembly;DTC's first peacetime dance; radio commercial article; poetry and creative writing; "What Do You Think" article on returning male students; Freshman elections, Athletic Association election; freshman class picnic.
    October 1946, Volume III, No. 5 Dr. Ralph Jenkins dies; "We Will Remember" editorial; DTC officers; men's basketball; "Hurrah for Postcards" article on sending short notes on postcards versus letters; summer activities by students; new faculty member Mr. John J. Murphy.
    November 1946, Volume III, No. 6 Dean Haas elected President; Junior play to be "Claudia;" first major celebration held by seniors will be reunion dance at the Hotel Green; Literary Section; Miss Cora Jane Russell honored; Assembly hears Mr. Otto Borch speak on the World Student Service Fund; Freshman class officers.
    December 1946, Volume III, No. 7 Miss Claire G. Trisch becomes new Dean; Dr. Sutton, former professorof History at DSTC honored at formal dinner; Literary Secion; Kappa Delta Pi activities; Sale of school banners by the sophomore class; Freshman chemistry class visits Margerie Water Reservoir.
    January 1947, Vol. III, No. 8 DSTC may see building plans approved; Editorial concerning CGA and its activities; Literary Section; campus news; debate on "Equal Pay for Equal Work for Women;" Drama Club news.
    February 1947, Vol. III, No. 9 Sweetheart Ball successful; Mr. Joseph Abrahams crowned Queen; Dr. Lewis Paul Todd article; Literary Section; Music Department expanding.
    April 1947, Vol. III, No. 11 [Election Special Edition] Candidates for President, Vice President, Recording Secretary, Treasurer, and Publicity Secretary, and excerpts from the Constitution of the Cooperative Government Association.
    May 1947, Vol. III, No. 11 Photograph of cast members of Junior Class play "Claudia;" Athletic Association Banquet; Literary Section; Classroom Chatter; Assembly News; Comments on "The Greek Situation;" CGA officers for 1947-48; post season basketball.
    June 1947, Vol. III, No. 12 Senior class photograph; Seniors Receives Degrees; Editorial "To The Seniors;" Sports Parade, Literary Section, Odds and Ends column; Class election results; Senior-Faculty Banquet.
  - What's My Name "I'm your paper; name me," November 1947, 42087 (Box 2)
    November 1947, Vol. I, No. 1 "What's My Name? edition; Editorial Board seeks name for paper from student boy; DTC CGA adopts new constitution; Eruma Society [Mature rearranged spelling by male students]; Editorial Board of School Publication photograph (identified); Mr.Carl A. Pettersch new history teacher; phonograph with six head phones to be installed in the library; Mr. Stanley Glowacki joins music department; AA program accelerates under new leaders; Cheer leaders selected in October; basketball news; Dr. Alic Donnelly new gym teacher; Student Forum elects officers.
  - The Courier, February 1948 through June 1954, 1948-1954; 42086 (Box 4)
    February 1948, Vol. I, No. 3 DTC to attend Eastern States Conference for Professional Teachers Colleges; Forum members Helen Platt and Carl Paight, along with other Connecticut colleges, attend meeting to plan Mock Legislature; Courier staff changes; Erutma to give play; Do-Day Editorial; Literary Section; Sports Scope by Cosbeck; Men's Intramurals.
    April 1948, Vol. I, No. 5 Juniors initiate means for curriculum study; First "Do-Day" ushered in; Kappa Delta Pi initiation; News Briefs; Literary contest; Gossip column "Aunt Gertrude;" Sports Scope" column; Music Department News; Fairfield Hall to have written set of rules; Sophomore class announce carnival.
    May 1948, Vol. I, No. 6 Junior play "Berkeley Square" a hit; senior class activities; Three Cheers Column choice is Prof. John Murphy; CGA election returns; Editorial on months events; Literary Contest: Delegates to Mock Legislature named; News Briefs column; "Aunt Gertrude" column; Junior Travelogue; Sports Scope column; "Do Day Was Big Day" column; "Our War Baby" column gives background of child DTC is sponsoring though the Foster Parents Plan for Orphaned War Children.
    November 1948, Vol. II, No. 1 Forum gives timely discussion on "The Political Parties and the Coming Elections; AA starts first year under new plan; Danbury Choral Society prepares for coming season; Three Cheers Column goes to Joe Allo, includes picture of Joe Alllo and his son; Editorial on Tom Curley's death; Sports Scope; new part-time psychology instructor Mr. Edmond J. Cain; new departmental plan defines students as "Elementary and General Education, Music Education, and Junior Engineering and Lab. Tech." rather than by Freshman and Sophomore classes; News Briefs column.
    February 1949, Vol. II, No. 2 DTC receives letters from foster child; "The Night of January 16th" annual school play; New Courier editors; Erutma new officers chosen; Sports Scope column; Senior Scoops, DTC orchestra to present concert; News Briefs; Science Department news; Junior Class officers.
    March 1949, Vol. II, No. 3 Thomas F. Curley honored at Dedication of Hut, Recreation Hut now call Curley Hall; Neil Wagner profile; Curriculum Committee has difficult task and requires student cooperation; Dramatic Club News; Editorial on CGA's closure of Curley Hall; Music Department students and faculty travel to Baltimore and Washington, DC; Do-Day article; creative writing "A Sad Study In Black or The Life of Mort Tician;" Cast and stage crew of "The Night of January 16" photograph and review of play; Senior Scoops.
    June 1949, Vol. II, No. 4 Last dance for class of '49; Tony Mercadante elected president of CGA; Do-Day Deans Tony Sagnella and Nill Koulbanis; Science Department news; Sports Scope; Happy Hearts column; poetry corner; Music Education Department news; Senior Scoops.
    October 1949, Vol. III, No. 2 New staff leaders for Courier; Literary contest; Kappa Delta Pi news; Editorial on Curley Hall; Roving Reporter column; poems by students; Sports column; Curriculum Committee news; Erutma News; Music and Science News.
    March 1950, Vol. III, No. 3 Miss Yonush, the "mother" of the dorm girls profiled; Olga Zukowsky, President of the General and Elementary Educaion Department and treasurer of Form profile; Dramatic Workshop to present "You Can't Take It With You;" Moc Legislature to be held next week at the state capitol; Who's Who? column; Roving Reporter; Do-Day Communique; CGA sponsoring a Vigilante Committee to help regulate conditions in Curley Hall; Creative writing "The Clock" by Harold Walker, and "Retaliation" by John Coyle; poetry by D. Kurt Singer and Bruce Haeger; "Dream Street" mustical comedy written; Junior class trip to Washington, D. C.' Erutma News; Kappa Delta Pi, Senior News; and Public Relations Committee News.
    April 6, 1950, Vol. III, No. 4 DTC proposes Laws in Mock Legislature; Personalities focus on Bud Sisterhemn and Bob Case; Roving Reporter; Platter Chatter by Don Dempsey; Sport Scope; Letter to the Editor: Present departmental organization headed for chaos; Mardi Gras sponsored by the General and Elementary Education Department; new Science Building; Library news.
    April 21, 1950, Vol. III, No. 5 Do-Day Dean Candidates and photographs; Mardi Gras a success; The Voice of '51; Sports Scope, Who's Who? column; Senior May Day; Music Deparment's trip to St. Louis Conference; Parent-Teachers enjoy tour of DTC; Roving Reporter; G.E.E Assembly.
    May 23, 1950, Vol. III, No.6 Do-Day Deans, Florence Hossan and Harry Forsberg, take over day's activities; College to present "You Can't Take It With You;" Junior News; May Day Program; Sports Scope; Who's Who? articles; poetry by Jerry Musson and D. Kurt Singer; "May 10, 1950!! or The day after Do-Day" cartoon "Do we gotta go to Class?" Around the clock at DTC; Senior Post Training Notes; "At Last" news about seniors.
    June 16, 1950, Vol. III, No. 7 Barbara Austin and Paul Gillotti first music majors to graduate from DTC; Commencement; "You Can't Take It With You" a hit; G.E.E.D. Department news; A.A. News; Senior News; Who's Who? Class Will; Platter Chatter; Dorm Officers; Music Department picnic; Science Department News; Junior Prom, and Roving Reporter.
    October 11, 1950 Third annual CGA banquet; Mr. Otav Sundet, advisor to the Ministry of Education at Oslow, Norway, visits college; Yearbook u nder way; Junior News, Kapp Delta Phi and Library Committee news; Interim interviews begin; Senior news; Dots and Dashes column on campus news; "The Question of Academic Freedom" by Joe Leheney; "A Plea for Understaing" [differences between Americans and Europeans] by Lyman S. Burbank; Sports Scope; AA sponsoring Halloween Dance; "A Better Athletic Program" article.
    November 2, 1950 Courier to begin school-wide poll today and tomorrow to determine how well informed students and teachers are; Wayne Engle, freshman assistant editor; Reverend Craw speaks at Forum; Irene Fenick elected queen of the Danbury Hat Parade; Fred Canfield becomes President of the CGA; Erutma membership drive ends soon; President's Corner; Women's AA in Intramurals; news briefs; "Sophisticated Lady" prom.
    December 4, 1950 Student Study Curriculum and Committee's proposals presented to school; Drama Workshop; Juniors hold carnival; Mock Legislature; Basketball season opens; AA news; "The Twenty-Fifth Hour; from Fables to Facts" by J. Leheny.
    December 15, 1950 Annual Christmas concert presented by the Danbury Choral Society was shared by the Dramatic Club of the college; Bills sent to mock legislature; Mr. Petteresch at United Nations; Forum speaker Dr. Lyman Burbank on "Contemporary Europe;" Who's Who? column; Sports News; The Sweeper column; "The Clock" by Harold Walker.
    March 19, 1951 DTC students recognize problem of Curley Hall; names accepted for Who's Who; Thirty students attend Hartford session; Irish square dance; Delegates elected to Eastern States; State Department of Educaion's new rules for teacher certification; Propspects for male enrollment; sophomore ideas on curriculum; "Moroccan Situation" by Al. Hajj; "Accelerated College" by J. Leheny; The Sweeper column; Do-Day planning underway; Faculty news; The Chorus will present "Iolanthe" for its spring concert; Sports news; Photograph of Varsity Basketball Team.
    April 11, 1951 Forty DTC delegates attend Eastern States Conference; The Drama Workshop presented "Doll's House;" Editorial to clarify the purpose and policy of the Courier; Draft deferment tests; Senior News; Photograph of students making a wish by the well in the "Spring Garden;" Tentative four year curriculum structure has been drawn up by the Curriculum Committee; Who's Who? by M. J. Mulrooney; "Impressions of Mexico" by George LaCava; Juniors elect Do-Day Deans; Forum News.
    May 1, 1951 DTC to present "Lolanthe", Production to benefit college yearbook for 1952; Curriculum plan in final stages; seniors sign for positions after graduation; Conference presents outlines for peace by Pauline Randall; C.E.A. Council news; WAA intramurals in final stages; "Just Ramblin'" by Dot Shaw; Culture and Scholarship at DTC by Jerry Musson; origin of Do-Day; Words and Music by Williard S. Starbard; Duford and Tahan Do-Day Deans; The Sweeper column by Mitzi.
    June 12, 1951 Rabbi Malino speaker at Baccalaureate service; Vincent Cibarelli to head CGA; Senior-Faculty graduation banquet; Dr. Alpenfels, Associate Professor of Education at NYU, to address graduates; Five faculty members to retire; Iran Oil Situation by Alfred Hajj; Sophomores elect new officers; "Incident in Calcutta" by Herb Coleman; "Nature At Its Best" by Wayne Engle; The Sweeper column by Mitzi; Music Department officers; Sports news; AA banquet at Lakeview.
    September 24, 1951 The Courier welcomes DTC Freshmen; Eight New Faculty; Miss Claire Trisch visits Europe; The Interim Program; President's Corner; The Library column; The Sweeper by Myrt and Olga; CGA information; Business column by Lyman B. Burbank; Washington Sidelights by Dot Hogan; Voice of the Frosh; A Junio and Soph Suggests; AA first social event.
    November 19, 1951 German Professor, Dr. Walter Kamm, Studies DTC System; Muriel Pronovost chosen yearbook editor; Miss Peggy Scanlon joins library staff; DTC observes education week; Curley Hall is changing; The Koren Story by Alfred Hajj; Jazz on Parade by Marie and Joe; Students attend NY Herald Tribune Forum; Faculty news; Forum begins; campus events; winners of the AA Masquerade; Playday at DTC; Clean-up Campaign in Curley Hall; Sports.
    December 12, 1951 Chorus and Orchestra in Christmas Concert; Dr. Kamm honored; Seniors to give ball; Seniors separate again; The Sweeper column; Music Department will present its annual band and orchestrat concert; WAA Intramurals; Photograph of basketball team (identified); AA skating party; Varsity basketball; America, My Homeland by Elsie M. Smith.
    April 8, 1952 Headline: Dwight D. Eisenhower Our Choice"; Co-Ed Capers a great success; Mary Gillotti chosen yearbook editor; Kappa Delta Phi Initiates; Music educators meet in Philadelphia; Training School news; Asia--The Giant by Alfred Hajj; Men's sports; Eastern States Conference; WAA News; Students attend International Relations Forum.
    May 20, 1952 Cibbarelli and George elected officers of the CGA; Work begins on two new buildings; Groundbreaking for new building
  - The Supplement, April 1953 through November 1955, 1953-1955; 42085 (Box 2)
  - The Echo, November 1955 through June 1959, 1955-1959; 42084 (Box 2)
  - The Echo, October 1959 through November 1963, 1959-1963; 42083 (Box 3)
  - The Echo, January 1964 through December 1965, 1964-1965; 42082 (Box 5)
  - The Echo, January 1966 through December 1968, 1966-1968; 42081 (Box 6)
  - The Echo, January 1969 through December 1972, 1969-1972; 42080 (Box 7)
  - The Echo, January 1973 through December 1975, 1973-1975; 42079 (Box 8)
  - The Echo, January 1976 through December 1978, 1976-1978; 42078 (Box 9)
  - The Echo, February 1979 through December 1981, 1979-1981; 42077 (Box 10)
  - The Echo, January 1982 through December 1984, 1982-1984; 42076 (Box 11)
  - The Echo, February 1985 through December 1987, 1985-1987; 42075 (Box 12)
  - The Echo, January 1988 through December 1989, 1988-1989; 42074 (Box 13)
  - The Echo, January 1990 through December 1992, 1990-1992; 42073 (Box 14)
  - The Echo, January 1993 through December 1994, 1993-1994; 42072 (Box 15)
  - The Echo, January 1995 through December 1996, 1995-1996; 42071 (Box 16)
  - The Echo, January 1997 through December 1998, 1997-1998; 42070 (Box 17)
  - The Echo, January 1999 through December 2000, 1999-2000; 42069 (Box 18)
  - The Echo, January 2001 through December 2002, 2001-2002; 42068 (Box 19)
  - The Echo, January 2003 through December 2004, 2003-2004; 42067 (Box 20)
  - The Echo, February 2005 through December 2005, 42066 (Box 21)
  - The Echo, February 2006 through December 2006, 42065 (Box 22)
  - The Echo, February 2007 through December 2008, 2007-2008; 42064 (Box 23)
  - The Echo, February 2009 through December 2010, 2009-2010; 42063 (Box 24)
  - The Echo, February 2011through December 2015, 2011-2015; 57788 (Box 25)
    Currently missing volume LVII of 2011 Currently missing volume LVII of 2012 & LVIII of 2012 Issue #5 & LVIII of 2012 Issue #8 Currently missing volume LVIIII of 2013 Issue #2
  - Additional copies of: The Echo, 1936-1955; 42062 (Box Dup 1)
  - Additional copies of: The Echo, 1955-1963; 42061 (Box Dup 2)
  - Additional copies of: The Echo, 1937-1989; 42060 (Box Dup 3)
  - Additional copies of: The Echo, 1990-1999; 42059 (Box Dup 4)
  - Additional copies of: The Echo, 2000; 42058 (Box Dup 5)
  - Additional copies of: The Echo, 2001-2004; 42057 (Box Dup 6)
  - Additional copies of: The Echo, 2005-2007; 42056 (Box Dup 7)
  - Additional copies of: The Echo, 2008-2009; 42055 (Box Dup 8)